<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nishchal Bhandari</title>
    <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nishchal Bhandari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:29:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Break it up! Improving Your Godot Code Using Components</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/catnap_components/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:29:48 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/catnap_components/</guid>
      <description>As your Godot project grows, it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly important to keep your code and node structure organized to avoid it from resembling a particularly notorious kind of pasta. The Godot best practices recommends having scenes that are singularly focused and loosely coupled. How can we achieve that in practice? In this article, I will explain what is often called the Component pattern and go through some real-world examples from my recently released game Twinkle Stardust&amp;rsquo;s Catnap Chaos to demonstrate how you can use it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Procedural Eyebrow Shader in Godot</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/eyebrow_shader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 12:40:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/eyebrow_shader/</guid>
      <description>Shaders can be a mysterious topic for game developers not yet familiar with them. And seeing some of the wild things people can create with them (for example, on Shadertoy), they can even be ominous. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole new language and framework you have to learn in addition to Godot!&#xA;In this tutorial, I want to breakdown the process I used to create a simple procedural eyebrow shader for TriEdge Hack to help those who are learning about shaders but aren&amp;rsquo;t sure of the process of creating one from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Darktable: Painting With Light (or dodging and burning)</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_dodge_burn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 16:57:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_dodge_burn/</guid>
      <description>The above image is alright, but it has a big issue: the water, which should be the main subject, does not stand out. Instead, the diffuse lighting of the image draws attention to the sky and rocks. How can we draw more focus to the waterfall?&#xA;One technique we can use is &amp;ldquo;dodging and burning&amp;rdquo;, where we make selective tonal adjustments to parts of our image. In this post, I will show one such technique for doing this in darktable which I call &amp;ldquo;painting with light&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Better Movement in Godot</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/godot_building_better_movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 21:18:17 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/godot_building_better_movement/</guid>
      <description>How do you create a responsive character controller? What does responsive even mean for this? What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with using standard physics equation for this? This blog post will cover these questions and how you how to build responsive movement in Godot.&#xA;A lot of this post is inspired by great resources that you should also check out:&#xA;Math for Game Programmers: Building a Better Jump Math for Game Programmers: Fast and Funky 1D Nonlinear Transformations Game Feel, by Steve Swink Note that this post will demonstrate using Godot 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Darktable: Pastel Style</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_pastel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 21:23:30 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_pastel/</guid>
      <description>Pastel colors are a useful tool to have in your photography toolkit. Editing images with this style can help you take advantage of bright harsh light, lack of shadows, and colorful elements.&#xA;What is a pastel color? Wikipedia says they have &amp;ldquo;high value and low saturation&amp;rdquo;. With paint, you can achieve them by &amp;ldquo;mixing white&amp;rdquo; with your standard colors. But how can we do this in darktable?&#xA;To understand how we can accomplish this, its helpful to look at the diagrams in the darktable manual on color dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Darktable: Emulate Film Halation</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_halation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_halation/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across an article about the halation effect in film (check out that article if you are interested in a description of the effect). I wanted to emulate the effect using darktable, and thankfully the Diffuse or Sharpen module that was released in darktable 3.8 makes this pretty easy.&#xA;The method I will describe below is heavily based on one by one of the authors of the module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Darktable: Recreate this look #1</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt-recreate1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt-recreate1/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, someone asked online how to recreate the look of sanghan. Here is my attempt at showing how to do this using darktable 3.6.&#xA;Here is the end product of the edit. I found this image on Signature Edits&#xA;Here is our starting point. Notice that the conditions are similar to the images we are using as inspiration. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot easier to achieve a look when your lighting conditions are close.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
