<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Godot on Nishchal Bhandari</title>
    <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/tags/godot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Godot on Nishchal Bhandari</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:29:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nishchalb.github.io/tags/godot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Break it up! Improving Your Godot Code Using Components</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/catnap_components/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:29:48 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/catnap_components/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As your Godot project grows, it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly important to keep your code and node structure organized to avoid it from resembling&#xA;a particularly notorious kind of pasta. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.godotengine.org/en/stable/tutorials/best_practices/scene_organization.html&#34;&gt;Godot best practices&lt;/a&gt; recommends having scenes that are singularly focused and loosely coupled. How can we achieve that in practice? In this article, I will explain&#xA;what is often called the &lt;em&gt;Component pattern&lt;/em&gt; and go through some real-world examples from my recently released game&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/3050120/Twinkle_Stardusts_Catnap_Chaos&#34;&gt;Twinkle Stardust&amp;rsquo;s Catnap Chaos&lt;/a&gt; to demonstrate how you can use it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Procedural Eyebrow Shader in Godot</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/eyebrow_shader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 12:40:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/eyebrow_shader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shaders can be a mysterious topic for game developers not yet familiar with them. And seeing some of the wild things people can create&#xA;with them (for example, on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shadertoy.com/&#34;&gt;Shadertoy&lt;/a&gt;), they can even be ominous. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole new language and framework you have to learn in addition to Godot!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I want to breakdown the process I used to create a simple procedural eyebrow shader for &lt;a href=&#34;https://nishb.itch.io/triedge-hack&#34;&gt;TriEdge Hack&lt;/a&gt; to help those who are learning about shaders but aren&amp;rsquo;t sure of the process of creating one from scratch. Specifically, we will look at how to do this in a Godot 2D environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Better Movement in Godot</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/godot_building_better_movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 21:18:17 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/godot_building_better_movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you create a responsive character controller? What does responsive even mean for this? What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with using&#xA;standard physics equation for this? This blog post will cover these questions and how you how to build responsive movement in Godot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of this post is inspired by great resources that you should also check out:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hG9SzQxaCm8&#34;&gt;Math for Game Programmers: Building a Better Jump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mr5xkf6zSzk&#34;&gt;Math for Game Programmers: Fast and Funky 1D Nonlinear Transformations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.game-feel.com/&#34;&gt;Game Feel, by Steve Swink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that this post will demonstrate using Godot 3.4. KinematicBody2D has been renamed CharacterBody2D in Godot 4.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
