<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Nishchal Bhandari</title>
    <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Nishchal Bhandari</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:10:53 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>img-ditto</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/imgditto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:10:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/imgditto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nishchalb.github.io/imgditto-header.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nishchalb/img-ditto&#34;&gt;Project Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;concept&#34;&gt;Concept&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;img-ditto is a small python script with a command line interface that allows you to transfer the color style from&#xA;one image to another. It works by using the histogram matching technique on the channels of an image. Typically the&#xA;technique is used to equalize the intensity of an image to improve contrast, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the method works&#xA;decently well for color transfer as well. This implementation work well when the &amp;ldquo;to&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;from&amp;rdquo; images are similar in&#xA;content (both images are of a city, forest, etc.). The best transfers were typically in the LAB colorspace, but the&#xA;program lets you choose other colorspaces as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plane-Based Depth Image Completion</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/depth_completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:10:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/depth_completion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nishchalb.github.io/depthmodel.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kinect has encountered widespread use in the areas of 3D mapping and computer vision thanks to its low cost,&#xA;portability, and depth sensing capability. Unfortunately, its depth sensor has a maximum range of eight meters,&#xA;and past four meters it tends to be very noisy. This work presents an approach to augment the Kinect with the ability&#xA;to estimate the data that is missing from its sensors, providing a more complete picture of what is present in a given&#xA;scene. In contrast to much of what has been done, our work takes an approach more suited to the three-dimensional&#xA;structure of the world rather than relying on image processing techniques. We develop a model that utilizes image position, existing&#xA;depth, color, and surface normal measurements and derive an algorithm that can estimate missing data in a depth image using&#xA;only sensor data as input. Our results show that the generated estimates have a root mean square error of about 25 centimeters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secret Wizard Corporation</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/swc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:10:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/swc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nishchalb.github.io/wizard.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nishchalb.github.io/secret-wizard-corporation/&#34;&gt;Project Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;concept&#34;&gt;Concept&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secret Wizard Corporation is a small prototype game designed and created in two weeks by Nishchal Bhandari, Isaac Rosado, Pravina&#xA;Saratunga, and Rachel Thornton for the MIT class CMS.611/6.073 Creating Video Games. The game is designed as a flow puzzle&#xA;game with the addition of magical powers to help when players get stuck. To be successful, players must balance their&#xA;actions between traditional pipe rotations and magical abilities. The goal for this project was to develop a semi-polished game prototype&#xA;that featured an interesting trade-off as a mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>walltime</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/walltime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:10:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/walltime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nishchalb.github.io/walltime-header.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nishchalb/walltime&#34;&gt;Project Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;concept&#34;&gt;Concept&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;walltime is a small python script with a command line interface that can set the desktop wallpaper to an image&#xA;based on the time of day. walltime chooses an image semi-randomly that fits with the time of day. walltime works&#xA;by mapping the 24 hour clock to a color gradient (currently the viridis colormap in Matplotlib), and then finding images&#xA;who&amp;rsquo;s mean color is most similar to the color corresponding to the current time of day. Color distance is measured&#xA;in the LAB colorspace, where Euclidean distance closely matches perceptual differences in color.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
