<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nishchal Bhandari</title>
    <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nishchal Bhandari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 16:57:11 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nishchalb.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Darktable: Painting With Light (or dodging and burning)</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_dodge_burn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 16:57:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_dodge_burn/</guid>
      <description>The above image is alright, but it has a big issue: the water, which should be the main subject, does not stand out. Instead, the diffuse lighting of the image draws attention to the sky and rocks. How can we draw more focus to the waterfall?
One technique we can use is &amp;ldquo;dodging and burning&amp;rdquo;, where we make selective tonal adjustments to parts of our image. In this post, I will show one such technique for doing this in darktable which I call &amp;ldquo;painting with light&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Better Movement in Godot</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/godot_building_better_movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 21:18:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/godot_building_better_movement/</guid>
      <description>How do you create a responsive character controller? What does responsive even mean for this? What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with using standard physics equation for this? This blog post will cover these questions and how you how to build responsive movement in Godot.
A lot of this post is inspired by great resources that you should also check out:
Math for Game Programmers: Building a Better Jump Math for Game Programmers: Fast and Funky 1D Nonlinear Transformations Game Feel, by Steve Swink Note that this post will demonstrate using Godot 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darktable: Pastel Style</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_pastel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 21:23:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_pastel/</guid>
      <description>Pastel colors are a useful tool to have in your photography toolkit. Editing images with this style can help you take advantage of bright harsh light, lack of shadows, and colorful elements.
What is a pastel color? Wikipedia says they have &amp;ldquo;high value and low saturation&amp;rdquo;. With paint, you can achieve them by &amp;ldquo;mixing white&amp;rdquo; with your standard colors. But how can we do this in darktable?
To understand how we can accomplish this, its helpful to look at the diagrams in the darktable manual on color dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darktable: Emulate Film Halation</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_halation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt_halation/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across an article about the halation effect in film (check out that article if you are interested in a description of the effect). I wanted to emulate the effect using darktable, and thankfully the Diffuse or Sharpen module that was released in darktable 3.8 makes this pretty easy.
The method I will describe below is heavily based on one by one of the authors of the module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darktable: Recreate this look #1</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt-recreate1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/posts/dt-recreate1/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, someone asked online how to recreate the look of sanghan. Here is my attempt at showing how to do this using darktable 3.6.
Here is the end product of the edit. I found this image on Signature Edits
Here is our starting point. Notice that the conditions are similar to the images we are using as inspiration. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot easier to achieve a look when your lighting conditions are close.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>img-ditto</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/imgditto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:10:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/imgditto/</guid>
      <description>Project Page
Concept img-ditto is a small python script with a command line interface that allows you to transfer the color style from one image to another. It works by using the histogram matching technique on the channels of an image. Typically the technique is used to equalize the intensity of an image to improve contrast, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the method works decently well for color transfer as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plane-Based Depth Image Completion</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/depth_completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:10:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/depth_completion/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Kinect has encountered widespread use in the areas of 3D mapping and computer vision thanks to its low cost, portability, and depth sensing capability. Unfortunately, its depth sensor has a maximum range of eight meters, and past four meters it tends to be very noisy. This work presents an approach to augment the Kinect with the ability to estimate the data that is missing from its sensors, providing a more complete picture of what is present in a given scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secret Wizard Corporation</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/swc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:10:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/swc/</guid>
      <description>Project Page
Concept Secret Wizard Corporation is a small prototype game designed and created in two weeks by Nishchal Bhandari, Isaac Rosado, Pravina Saratunga, and Rachel Thornton for the MIT class CMS.611/6.073 Creating Video Games. The game is designed as a flow puzzle game with the addition of magical powers to help when players get stuck. To be successful, players must balance their actions between traditional pipe rotations and magical abilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>walltime</title>
      <link>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/walltime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:10:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishchalb.github.io/projects/walltime/</guid>
      <description>Project Page
Concept walltime is a small python script with a command line interface that can set the desktop wallpaper to an image based on the time of day. walltime chooses an image semi-randomly that fits with the time of day. walltime works by mapping the 24 hour clock to a color gradient (currently the viridis colormap in Matplotlib), and then finding images who&amp;rsquo;s mean color is most similar to the color corresponding to the current time of day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
